acumenfund.org 2019-05-10

# Acumen | Privacy Policy -

Privacy Policy

NOTICE OF PRIVACY PRACTICES FOR ACUMEN

At Acumen Fund, Inc. (“Acumen”), we understand and appreciate that your decision to choose us for your philanthropic investment is an expression of confidence. You trust us with your investment and you trust us to keep secure any information we obtain from you or about you. We understand that privacy is important, and we are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of both our current and prospective investors as well as visitors to our Website.

The following notice is designed to help you better understand the information we gather from investors and from those who visit acumenfund.org (the “Website”). It also describes how we handle the information once we gather it, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of the information. This Privacy Policy, together with the Terms of Use and Conditions, set out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to use, will be processed by us.  By sharing information with Acumen or by visiting this Website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

By using this Website, you consent to the use of information that you provide us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  We do update this Privacy Policy from time to time so please review this Privacy Policy regularly.  If we materially alter our Privacy Policy we will notify you of such changes by posting a notice on our Website. Your continued use of our Site will be deemed your agreement that your information may be used in accordance with the new policy. If you do not agree with the changes, then you should stop using the Website and notify us that you do not want your information used in accordance with the changes.

We have structured our Website so that you can visit it without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information.  If you choose to provide us with information by which you can be identified, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### WEBSITE PRIVACY NOTICE

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to fully understand how we collect, share and protect information about you.  This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is part of the Terms of Use and Conditions of this Website.  To access the Terms and Conditions of Use click [here](http://acumen.org/terms-of-use-and-conditions/).

By accessing and using the Website, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and that you accept and consent to the privacy practices and uses or disclosures of information about you that are described herein.

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Our primary goals in collecting personal information are to share information about our work, to invite you to events designed to update you on Acumen’s activities, to allow you to request information, and to thank you for your support. However, in order to deliver personalized and relevant information to you through our Website we collect certain information from users. Please do not provide any sensitive information or health information. If you should do so inadvertently, we will use and disclose that information in the same manner as any other information you provide to us as more fully described below.

In operating our website, we may collect and process the following data or information about you:

  * Personally identifiable information: 
    * If you make a donation to Acumen, we will request personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, address, phone number and email address. We seek such information to facilitate your donation and communicate with you about it. In addition, we may use this information to update you on Acumen’s work and to request your attendance at events such as our Investor Gathering to increase your knowledge of Acumen’s investments, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, and to answer any questions that you may have.
    * Unless you specify that a gift be “anonymous” or otherwise request that your name not be listed, we list the names of our Sustaining Partners, Partners & Associate Partners in our Website, brochures and other materials to recognize the generosity of those who support Acumen. We do not sell or rent our donor lists to anyone. We also do not share your personal data with any third parties other than service providers we employ to perform functions on our behalf, such as sending postal mail and email, processing credit card payments and organizing events specifically designed to keep you abreast of Acumen’s activities. These companies and individuals have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but are not authorized to use it for any other purpose.
  * If you post a comment on Acumen’s Website, Acumen will collect your name, email address, and your Website (if you choose to share your Website). Acumen may publicly display your name and Website with your comment, but your email address will not be published.
  * Non-personal information used primarily to provide an enhanced online experience, including, but not limited to traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, including your IP address, the date and time you accessed or left the Website and which pages you viewed, the type of operating system in use [e.g. Macintosh, Windows], the domain name, and the type of browser being used [e.g. Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer, etc.].

### USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

Acumen will not sell your personal information to third parties. However, Acumen will use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To share or disclose information with your consent.
  * To comply with applicable law, regulation or governmental request; protect safety of Acumen, Website users or others; protect the rights or property of Acumen; to comply with contractual obligations of Acumen; and, other instances when Acumen is legally required to disclose your information.
  * To share information that is public or does not include personal information, for example, aggregated data or a publicly posted comment.
  * To provide you with information relating to our services.
  * To provide third parties with statistical information about the users of our website.
  * To third parties if a you use certain third party features to share information about user activity through our Website, for example, the “Share” button on blog posts allows users to share posts on social networks. If you use these features, Acumen will share this information with the third party website or service, along with additional information you provide to use the feature (e.g., a Twitter username).  By accessing these third party websites, you are consenting to those terms and privacy policies of those websites.  You should read those third party website privacy policies and terms of use. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies whatsoever as we have no control over them.
  * To any affiliated business entities or third parties necessary to provide services to you, including, but not limited to, our subsidiaries, our holding company and its other subsidiaries (if any), as well as third parties involved in the administration and operation of our services.
  * To a third party if we sell any or all of our business and/or assets to them.

### USE OF COOKIES, AGGREGATE DATA COLLECTED ONLINE

Cookies are text files created by websites that transfer information to your computer. Cookies allow websites to remember information about a user, such as a user’s preferences when visiting the Website. As with most websites, Acumen, by itself and through third party services such as Google Analytics, uses cookies to evaluate use of the Website and improve services. You can generally opt to disable cookies in your browser. However, if you disable cookies, you may not be able to access certain parts of the Website or certain aspects of the Website may not work correctly.

We do not track or collect personally identifiable information about our Website users unless you choose to subscribe for Acumen updates via e-mail and/or make a donation through our Website.  Our Website does  not have the ability to respond to a ‘do not track’ signal on a user’s browser.

### SECURITY

We care about the security of your personal data and we employ commercially suitable physical, electronic, and managerial security techniques and procedures to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the organization, including encrypting financial donations using SSL. You should be aware, however, that no transmission of data over the Internet is 100% secure and that unauthorized third parties may unlawfully intercept or access private data. You provide us with this information at your own risk.

### THIRD PARTY WEBSITE INTERACTION

By accessing other third party websites through our Website you are consenting to the terms and privacy policies of those third party websites.  We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies whatsoever as we have no control over them.  We do not have control over whether third parties track a user’s online activities over time and across different websites. We do not have the ability to respond to ‘do not track’ signals in this regard.

### USERS ONLY OVER THE AGE OF 13

This Website is only intended for use by those who have reached age 13 and older.  By using our Website you are affirming that you are at least 13 years old.  Acumen does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. As noted in Acumen’s Terms of Use, by signing up for a user account or by using the Website, users certify that they are 13 years of age or older. If you believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided information to the Website, please notify Acumen at [lroland@acumen.org](mailto:lroland@acumen.org). We are not liable for any damages that may result from the user’s misrepresentation of age.

### PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

We may, from time to time, make changes to this Privacy Policy, based on your comments and our needs. The most current version of this Privacy Policy will always be available at <http://acumen.org/privacy-policy>. Any modifications will become effective immediately upon posting. By continuing to use the Website, you accept such modifications.

If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information, we will contact all donors directly, whether in writing, telephonically or via email, and notify all others by posting a prominent announcement on our Website.

### GOVERNING LAW

You agree that your use of this Website, this Privacy policy and any disputes relating thereto, shall be governed in all respects by the laws of the State of New York.

### HOW TO CONTACT US

Your privacy is important to Acumen, If you have any questions or concerns regarding Acumen’s Privacy Policy, please direct them to:

Lynn Roland, General Counsel

Acumen Fund, Inc.  
40 Worth Street, Suite 303  
New York, NY 10013

You may also send an email to [lroland@acumen.org](mailto:lroland@acumen.org)

We would like to thank our donors for selecting Acumen to make philanthropic investments, our prospective partners for considering Acumen and our visitors for taking the time to understand more about Acumen by browsing our Website.
